latrobe.edu.au 2019-07-31

# Website privacy statement, Statements, La Trobe University

La Trobe University (LTU) respects the privacy of your personal information by adhering to privacy laws. La Trobe's web site privacy statement outlines how the University will manage personal information collected through its web site. This statement does not extend to external web sites that have been linked to from the University web site; in these cases you should refer to the privacy statements provided on each external site, as the University is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of these external sites. This privacy statement will be periodically updated to reflect web site and privacy compliance development and planning at La Trobe University.

## Privacy laws

Personal information collected via the LTU web site, will comply with the Victorian Privacy and Data Protection Act (2014) and the Health Records Act 2001.

## Collecting, using and disclosing personal information

### Online forms and other applications

If you provide personal details during your visit to the La Trobe University web site, then we will only use and disclose your personal information for the purpose for which it was collected. This includes information collected via online forms, learning modules, events and training registration, subscribing to receive newsletters and blog comments. Any other type of use and disclosure will require your consent, or be in accordance with prescribed exemptions under privacy laws.

We may share data that you provide to us with trusted third party partners to help us perform statistical analysis, provide customer support and to offer more relevant and personalised content. Such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information for any other purposes and they are required to maintain the confidentiality and security of your information.

### Cookies, local storage and web analytics

Cookies and local storage values are small data files that are transferred to your web browser when you visit a website. These files contain pieces of information that help you navigate a website efficiently and also help the University with statistical information to facilitate general web site management, development and planning.

Cookies and local storage values store non-personal information such as (but not limited to) the server address and domain name of your internet service provider, date and time of your visit to the site, which pages you accessed on the La Trobe website, files you downloaded, address of the last site you visited and the type of browser you are using.

From time to time, we use third party web analytics including Google Analytics & Ad Services, Adobe Launch and Facebook:

  * To collect information about your interaction and usage of our website.
  * Use anonymous information about your website behaviour in order to show you relevant content on your return visits to the LTU website.
  * To inform, optimise and serve ads to you on relevant websites based on your past visits to our website to advertise LTU across a variety of third-party websites and measure the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns.

Users can find out more how Google uses information collected from our site via Google’s [Privacy Terms](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites).

### Opting out

Most web browsers are set to accept cookies. You can refuse to accept the use cookies by adjusting the settings on your web browser; however doing so may result in you not being able to use the full functionality of this website.

Users can find out more about controlling Google’s [ad personalisation](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites) and [managing cookies](https://policies.google.com/technologies/managing) via Google’s [Privacy Terms](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites).

Users can opt-out of Facebook’s use of cookies and Facebook Pixel Re-Marketing through their Facebook Account settings.

### Staff and student login

If you have used your staff or student login details to access the La Trobe University web site (whether on your personal device through the La Trobe University network or on a La Trobe University device) or accessed an email sent to you from La Trobe University, the cookie information may also be linked to your individual user profile. This information may be used to monitor, customize, and improve La Trobe University's services. La Trobe University will only use your personal information for the purposes for which it has been collected and in accordance with applicable privacy laws.

### Monitoring computer users

La Trobe University reserves the right to monitor all computer usage by La Trobe computer users for the purpose of ensuring compliance with applicable laws, University Statutes, in particular the [Use of Computer Facilities Statute 2009](https://www.latrobe.edu.au/__data/assets/file/0003/155424/Use-of-Computer-Facilities-Statute-2009.pdf), and Regulations, the Internet Code of Practice, University Procedures and Policies, and to maintain a secure and effective computing environment.

## Security

The La Trobe University web site does not guarantee secure transmission of information over the internet. Visitors should be aware that there are risks in transmitting information over the internet. If you are concerned about conveying your personal information over the internet, then you may wish to contact the University by telephone or mail.

Some parts of our website require usernames and passwords to be entered before a users personal information is accessible i.e logging in to receive exam results. This is to ensure that information is displayed only to the intended person. You should ensure that your password is kept securely and not disclosed to anyone else.

If you would like further information please email the University's [Privacy Officer](mailto:privacy@latrobe.edu.au).

 _Updated 31 January 2019._
